<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>

  <FrenchBriquet.label>French Infantry Briquet</FrenchBriquet.label>
  <FrenchBriquet.description>Standard French infantry blade designed as a sidearm in place of the Charleville musket.</FrenchBriquet.description>
  <FrenchBriquet.tools.0.label>handle</FrenchBriquet.tools.0.label>
  <FrenchBriquet.tools.1.label>blade</FrenchBriquet.tools.1.label>
  <FrenchBriquet.tools.2.label>point</FrenchBriquet.tools.2.label>

  <BritishOfficerSword.label>British Officer Sword</BritishOfficerSword.label>
  <BritishOfficerSword.description>Standard pattern British Officer sword. Exceptionally sharp, and extremely well made.</BritishOfficerSword.description>
  <BritishOfficerSword.tools.0.label>handle</BritishOfficerSword.tools.0.label>
  <BritishOfficerSword.tools.1.label>blade</BritishOfficerSword.tools.1.label>
  <BritishOfficerSword.tools.2.label>point</BritishOfficerSword.tools.2.label>

  <Bullet_Musket.label>MinieBullet</Bullet_Musket.label>
  <Bullet_Rifle.label>MinieBullet</Bullet_Rifle.label>

  <CharlevilleMusket.label>Charleville Musket</CharlevilleMusket.label>
  <CharlevilleMusket.description>Standard pattern Charleville musket, designed in 1777 as a standard infantry musket. Muzzleloaded, with a slow reload time but devastating power behind the bullet. Bullets fired from these weapons were often lead, which in turn resulted in many infections and amputations from wounds caused by these weapons.</CharlevilleMusket.description>
  <CharlevilleMusket.tools.0.label>bayonet</CharlevilleMusket.tools.0.label>
  <CharlevilleMusket.tools.1.label>stock</CharlevilleMusket.tools.1.label>

  <BrownBessMusket.label>Brown Bess Musket</BrownBessMusket.label>
  <BrownBessMusket.description>Land pattern Brown Bess musket. Heavier than its french counterpart, resulting in a slightly longer reload time but more accurate fire. Muzzleloaded, with a slow reload time but devastating power behind the bullet. Bullets fired from these weapons were often lead, which in turn resulted in many infections and amputations from wounds caused by these weapons.</BrownBessMusket.description>
  <BrownBessMusket.tools.0.label>bayonet</BrownBessMusket.tools.0.label>
  <BrownBessMusket.tools.1.label>stock</BrownBessMusket.tools.1.label>

  <BakerRifle.label>Baker Rifle</BakerRifle.label>
  <BakerRifle.description>Baker rifle. Standard weapon assigned to rifle regiments in the British army. Highly accurate, but require an extensive reload time. Muzzleloaded, with a slow reload time but devastating power behind the bullet. Bullets fired from these weapons were often lead, which in turn resulted in many infections and amputations from wounds caused by these weapons.</BakerRifle.description>
  <BakerRifle.tools.0.label>bayonet</BakerRifle.tools.0.label>
  <BakerRifle.tools.1.label>stock</BakerRifle.tools.1.label>

  <Potsdam.label>Potsdam 1809 Musket</Potsdam.label>
  <Potsdam.description>New model musket replacing the ancient 1740 Frederick musket. Lighter and faster to reload than other weapons, the cartridge is slightly smaller and wounds somewhat less, but carries a slightly better range than French and British counterparts. Bullets fired from these weapons were often lead, which in turn resulted in many infections and amputations from wounds caused by these weapons.</Potsdam.description>
  <Potsdam.tools.0.label>bayonet</Potsdam.tools.0.label>
  <Potsdam.tools.1.label>stock</Potsdam.tools.1.label>

  <PrussianBriquet.label>Prussian Briquet</PrussianBriquet.label>
  <PrussianBriquet.description>Standard Prussian infantry blade designed as a sidearm or infantry officer weapon.</PrussianBriquet.description>
  <PrussianBriquet.tools.0.label>handle</PrussianBriquet.tools.0.label>
  <PrussianBriquet.tools.1.label>blade</PrussianBriquet.tools.1.label>
  <PrussianBriquet.tools.2.label>point</PrussianBriquet.tools.2.label>


</LanguageData>